<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SoftwareEngineering on Riyaz Ali</title><link>https://riyazali.net/tags/softwareengineering/</link><description>Recent content in SoftwareEngineering on Riyaz Ali</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-in</language><copyright>© Riyaz Ali</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://riyazali.net/tags/softwareengineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why documentation matters</title><link>https://riyazali.net/posts/why-documentation-matters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riyazali.net/posts/why-documentation-matters/</guid><description>tl;dr Good documentation gives the developers the necessary control to maintain a system - nochance @ stackexchange
But good code doesn&amp;rsquo;t need documentation 🤔 Remember, documentation go way beyond the comments that are inserted in code. Often times, they&amp;rsquo;re a combination of well describing code comments, design documents, business requirement documents and other relevant pieces.
Ain’t nobody got time for that ⏰ The main reason code goes undocumented is because of time!</description></item><item><title>Git Workflow</title><link>https://riyazali.net/posts/git-workflow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riyazali.net/posts/git-workflow/</guid><description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to write about the fork-clone-pull that we&amp;rsquo;ve been using for some time now at work.
To begin with, the Fork workflow (just workflow from now on) extend Github&amp;rsquo;s Workflow and adds forking to the mix..
And why do that? Several benefits.
You don&amp;rsquo;t need to give everyone write access to the central repository It keeps the central repository &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; (arguable..) by not polluting it with developers' feature branches Developers can form subteams (by adding other dev&amp;rsquo;s clone as a remote) (useful for collaborating, pair-programming etc.</description></item><item><title>Design Docs</title><link>https://riyazali.net/posts/design-docs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riyazali.net/posts/design-docs/</guid><description>A design doc — also known as a technical spec — is a description of how you plan to solve a problem. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the most useful tool for making sure the right work gets done.
It&amp;rsquo;s just more overhead man.. 🤷‍♂️ people often claim that it’s because they’re saving time by skipping the spec-writing phase.
But what they don&amp;rsquo;t realise is that in the long run (even for a smaller project that&amp;rsquo;s true), they might be spending a lot more time fixing, iterating and communicating all the same stuff (over and over again) what they could have done once if they had written a proper spec for it.</description></item></channel></rss>