<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Android on Riyaz Ali</title><link>https://riyazali.net/tags/android/</link><description>Recent content in Android on Riyaz Ali</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-in</language><copyright>© Riyaz Ali</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://riyazali.net/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Google Image Proxy</title><link>https://riyazali.net/posts/google-image-proxy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riyazali.net/posts/google-image-proxy/</guid><description>Continuing with app that I created as a project for the Udacity Android Nanodegree program, I faced a new challenge! The challenge was to load poster images from TMDb Image server inside my app!
Is it even a challenge? One could say that I could&amp;rsquo;ve simply used a library like Picasso or Glide to offload image loading to the tried and trusted tools. But my main challenge was not just to load the image but to load the perfect image.</description></item><item><title>Android Support Paging Library</title><link>https://riyazali.net/posts/android-support-paging-library/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riyazali.net/posts/android-support-paging-library/</guid><description>Recently, I was working on a project for the Udacity Android Nanodegree program to develop an Android application for TMDb to list movies using the TMDb API.
As you might&amp;rsquo;ve guessed, TMDb has a huge collection of movies, and so a need for paging the data was quite obvious from the very begining of the project.
So I started looking into ways in which I could&amp;rsquo;ve implemented paging with my RecyclerView.</description></item><item><title>Discourse Login on Android</title><link>https://riyazali.net/posts/discourse-login-on-android/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://riyazali.net/posts/discourse-login-on-android/</guid><description>A few days back, I was looking for a hobby side-project to work on. I wanted to develop an Android application (open source) and to collaborate with my peers on Google Udacity Android scholarship program. On the Udacity discussion forum, there were many threads filled with exciting ideas but they all were either too ambitious or required quite a bit of time.
Then, one day while checking into the forum an idea struck me!</description></item></channel></rss>